uh how do I do this do is this thing on
is this thing on um so we were you know
we here jamming looking at Mike St mik
holders around my neck and all this kind
of thing and somebody asked a question
which is very relevant to the beginner
boost so I'm going to go ahead and make
a video about it and publish it to
YouTube today and um they root has
agreed to let us use their name so I'm
going to go ahead and read it straight
up so this is from
r00t uh the message says I recently got
a cka certified what else should I learn
to become a kubernetes engineer everyone
says I should have a githead profile
what can I put
into um it got cut off what can I put
into it I guess I I mean you can figure
this out this isn't too hard the um the
answer is pretty simple um the C the
certification if anything is just one
tiny step of you getting a job there all
the rest of the stuff necessary to get a
job unfortunately the hard stuff uh
Still Remains to be done
um I could
redo probably two hours of videos that
I've already done about what the steps
are to get a job and how employment is
about trust and how you need to
establish a professional Learning
Network and you need to not spam people
with your rumes and you need to know
what to put in your rum all of these
things but I'm just going to refer to
that stuff um if you go to skill. SK i l
s ak. you can go there if you like it
you can you know sponsor me or do
whatever you want in your own way this
is all free content um the important
thing to take away from this is that and
I'm I'm going to use one direct critical
story to answer this question and um
I've answered this I've used this story
before in other to answer other material
but it's relevant so um I had I had
somebody Porsche fil actually this their
name um I they I don't know I've never
been able to confirm this with many of
people that I talked to in my learning
Comm Comm but they claim to be a senior
architect at a at a very uh prominent um
institution that most people would know
and they I I believe I believe it was
them I believe it was them I could be
mistaken on this if I'm if I'm mistaken
please correct me but it was somebody in
a high-end architectural leadership role
who regularly hangs out on my stream um
which I really love I've got a lot of
veterans in there who are you know very
opinionated and very experienced and
it's wonderful that's why I love having
the mix of veterans and and you know
beginners and this topic of creating a
getting a certificate came up versus
having a lab and and by lab I mean
either you know however you define a lab
whether the lab is a bunch of machines
in the cloud that you've organized or
it's um you know a bunch of Optiplex you
know refurbished Optiplex that you have
you know installed uh cni on and
everything like that which by the way
they don't test you on on the
certification you got a cka but good
good luck knowing what a storage class
is or setting up your own cni none of
that stuff is covered by the by the by
the
certificate and it's really critical
because knowing how to set up your own
round robin DNS knowing your Lo load
balancers all this stuff they cover some
of that stuff in with regard to the
cluster but they do not cover that stuff
um the only way to do that is to set up
so today at work a very real uh real-
time example of this um we had some
issues and we were going through
kubernetes and everything and some
people are in the team are trying to add
some new nodes and they're having
problems with Pixie boot right so they
can't they can't instantiate Network
bootable nodes by not having pixie boot
none of that is covered in the cka none
of that infrastr infrastructure
engineering none of those requirements
are covered in the
cka in fact when I went to go get my job
the job I eventually got it was
primarily to be a kubernetes
administrator and since I've become uh
an
uh high performance back in systems
developer by title uh when they came me
this the story about that when they they
hired me P time and they changed my
title I went from being a senior
infrastructure engineer to being that
I'm like oh okay cool because that I've
been spending almost all my time writing
goo doing API integration and and open
shift dancable integration and you know
dynamic delivery from with u you know
sort of Dev opsy things anyway the point
is that they told me you do do not need
kubernetes you don't need it I'm I mean
and I was like what are you talking
about this is a kubernetes role and I'm
like I just told you I don't have any
solid kubernetes experience and like
yeah you can learn it so I got a
kubernetes job for to become a
kubernetes administrator and I had no
kubernetes knowledge I said well fine
we'll give you a couple months to work
on that while you're working on other
things your other infrastructure
experience overwhelmingly proves that
you're the person for this job and that
you'll be able to pick this up no no
problem over time I want to tell you
something I I was I was 55 when that
happened and I was
overwhelmed with impostor syndrome
because I you know I was all of a sudden
doing something and being called on to
do all these things that I could and I
boy I I dove into everything um I looked
up step online I I practiced things I
built my own clusters uh I started
streaming about it a lot I talked to a
lot of people online and built that up
um the point is the cka wouldn't have
done it I got that job without a cka and
I'm not that's not a flex that's that's
just telling you the reality the reality
is is that if you have the if you can
demonstrate your ability to learn and
pick things up and you have a general
expertise in infrastructure
engineering the applications are going
to come and go they're going to come and
go the big-time applications they're
going to circulate through turns out to
be I know it's hard to say but
kubernetes eventually will you know
it'll be the end of its day but so cka
is at best you know a starting point you
still need to leverage the network you
need to find make contacts with people
you need to find to network you know go
to conferences or whatever to meet
people go to meetups in particular those
are better than conferences you don't
pay and then you can you know hang out
with people and get you know beer or
something and then you need to make
those connections the professional
connections you need to go online and do
that and and then the cka can be a part
of uh a bunch of things that are going
to get you that are going to get you the
job right so um but again there so
there's two two very specific pieces of
of of advice that I would I would person
say and you know I'm just one voice out
there there's lots of other people you
can ask please come in our community
please come in our Discord and ask other
professionals what they think
particularly het Tannis hore tnis
somebody working very regularly in this
space uh alt 4 also somebody who's
regularly in this space um there's lots
of other really great streamers on
Twitch and elsewhere who work in this
space please make sure you look for
people who are employed currently doing
this and and ask them what they think
but the two pieces of advice that I'll
give you that I really hold with is
build that professional Learning Network
and all that other stuff that goes with
it make sure you cover those videos
those videos are on I've done videos
about that and the second is make sure
you have built a kubernetes cluster from
the ground up on
Hardware not in the
cloud right oh look at
that they agreed with me it agreed with
me so number two gets me gets me
balloons I forgot about that the P sign
gets me b um so those that's my advice
my advice is make a network Hardware lab
build your own kubernetes cluster that
boots by turning the node on and off
that means understanding everything
about networking ever understanding
everything about Pixie booting
understanding everything about you know
boot from
https um these are all modern methods
for bringing Hardware online and that
will help you become you know a real
true kubernetes administrator if if you
are shooting for kubernetes
administrator jobs where you're only
administering kubernetes clusters that
exist that exist out there in the cloud
uh you know G GK what is it gke and the
Amazon one and all those if that's your
goal then great you probably would do
better at that because they those
Services provide as cni and you know all
of those things they they they they fill
in the gaps of all that but if you truly
want to understand kubernetes you can't
understand it until you've deployed all
those things for yourself that's all bye